<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Authors | Sasha Azad</title>
    <link>/authors/</link>
      <atom:link href="/authors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Authors</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 16:45:35 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Authors</title>
      <link>/authors/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/sasha/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 16:45:35 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/sasha/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am a Ph.D. Computer Science student in the Principles of Expressive Machines (POEM) Lab under the advisement of Dr. Chris Martens, at NC State University. I model and study large populations of humans by simulating small-scale social interactions that take into account real-world geographic constraints, logistics, lifestyles, and social influence dynamics. With my research I aim to support a variety of applications, such as examining the implications of social science theories and developing playable, explorable story worlds. I believe my research would afford increased entertainment, immersion and replayability for users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prior to NC State, I was a Research Lab Associate Intern at Disney Research Pittsburgh under the advisement of Dr. Boyang Li in the Narrative Intelligence Lab. Before that I completed my M.S. in Computer Science from Georgia Institute of Technology under the advisement of Dr. Mark Riedl in the Entertainment Intelligence Lab.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/chris/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 16:04:51 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/chris/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am an assistant professor in the Computer Science (CSC) Department at NC State, where I direct the Principles of Expressive Machines (POEM) Lab. My interests span programming languages, automated reasoning (logic/symbolic AI), and computational media (digital games and interactive storytelling).
Previously, I was a postdoc with the Expressive Intelligence Studio at UC Santa Cruz, and I did my Ph.D. in the Principles of Programming Group at CMU.
My pronouns are they/them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Website: &lt;a href=&#34;https://sites.google.com/ncsu.edu/cmartens/home&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://sites.google.com/ncsu.edu/cmartens/home&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chris Martens</title>
      <link>/authors/chris-martens/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/chris-martens/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sasha Azad</title>
      <link>/authors/sasha-azad/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/sasha-azad/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
